Finding Aid for Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs (University of Michigan) publications, 1987-1999
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs (University of Michigan) publications
1987-1999
University of Michigan. Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs.
9939 Bimu 2
Publications of the office of Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs include annual reports, bibliographies, handbooks and manuals, newsletters entitled Beyond Diversity and the OMA Update, reports, and surveys. Also includes brochures, flyers, and proposals from the King/Chavez/Parks Educational Initiative.
1 linear feet
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor no. 8046 )
Periodic additions to the records expected.
Publications are open for research.
For historical note, please consult the finding aid Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs (University of Michigan) Records.
Publications of the office of Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs include annual reports, bibliographies, handbooks and manuals, newsletters entitled Beyond Diversity and the OMA Update, reports, and surveys. Also includes brochures, flyers, and proposals from the King/Chavez/Parks Educational Initiative. The Publications are divided into three series: Unit Publications and Sub-Unit Publications.
Subjects:
Minority college students--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; Multiculturalism--Michigan.; University of Michigan. Office of Academic Multicultural Initiatives.; University of Michigan. Office of Minority Affairs.; University of Michigan. Vice Provost for Academic and Multicultural Affairs.; University of Michigan. Vice Provost for Minority Affairs.; Directory of diversity programs.
Contributors:
University of Michigan. Vice Provost for Minority Affairs.; University of Michigan. Office of Minority Affairs.; University of Michigan. Office of Academic Multicultural Initiatives.; Wade McCree Incentive Scholars.; Moody, Christella D. Journey through South Africa. 1991.; Moody, Christella D. Personal journey through South Africa. 1991.
Genre Terms:
Annual reports.; Anthologies.; Bibliographies.; Manuals.; Newsletters.; Posters.; Programs.; Schedules.
- Unit Publications
  The Unit Publications series contains three annual reports, including One Year Later...Commitment to Leadership: Annual Report on Minority Affairs from 1988. Two types of guidebooks are found in this series. Campus Connections is the name given to a pamphlet published by the VPAMA to list for minority students the resources available for them on campus. The other guidebook, A Checklist for a Multicultural University, is directed toward the implementers of University programs to encourage multiculturalism at the University. Also in this series are two versions of a report containing photographs and anecdotes by Charles Moody about his trip to South Africa in 1991, where he met with Nelson Mandela to present him with an award from the University. The completed questionnaires from the Survey of Minority Activities conducted in 1989 are found under Surveys in this series.
  - Announcements, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Annual Reports
    - One Year Later...Commitment to Leadership: Annual Report on Minority Affairs, 1988 (Box 1)
    - OVPMA Update, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Bibliographies
    - A Partial List of Materials Available for Research on the History of Educational Equity for African-Americans at the U of M, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Brochures, 1987; undated (Box 1)
  - Calendars
    - Black History Month Schedules, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Collage, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
  - Conferences/Retreats
    - Diversity Resource Forum
      - Brochures, 1991 (Box 1)
      - Directory of Diversity Programs, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Hispanic Leadership Conference, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Programs (Miscellaneous), 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Retreat on the Multicultural University, 1994 (Box 1)
    - Superintendents' Forum
      - Flyers, 1988 (Box 1)
      - Invitations, 1988 (Box 1)
      - Programs, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - The U of M Office of Minority Affairs Salutes the Historically and Predominantly Black and Predominantly Hispanic Colleges and Universities, 1988 (Box 1)
    - The University Since BAM: Twenty Years of Progress?
      - Brochures, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Invitations, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Reports, 1990 (Box 1)
      - Schedules, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Flyers, 1988-1994 (Box 1)
  - Guidebooks
    - Campus Connections, 1993/1994-1996/1997 (Box 1)
    - A Checklist for a Multicultural University, 1991; undated (Box 1)
  - Invitations, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Operating Policies and Procedures Manual, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Beyond Diversity, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - OMA Update, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - Educational Collaboration programs, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Reports
    - Faculty, Staff and Students of Color: A Statistical Profile for 1982/83 through 1992/93, 1983/84 through 1993/94 (Box 1)
    - A Journey through South Africa, 1991 (Box 1)
    - Reflections: A Personal Journey through South Africa, 1992 (Box 1)
    - Selected Tables from the Michigan Study Report on the Entering Class of 1990 Experiences with Diversity, 1995 (Box 1)
    - Strategies and Techniques for Pipeline Development and Recruitment of Underrepresented Students of Color, 1992-1993 (Box 1)
    - Update on Student Retention and Academic Progress at the U of M, Ann Arbor 1978-1982 An Analysis of the Freshman Retention File Data, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Student publications
    - The Circle: A Native American Resource Guide, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
    - Exito: A Latina/o Handbook, 1998-1999 (Box 1)
  - Surveys
    - Survey of Minority Activities Questionnaire, 1989 (Box 1)
- Sub-Unit Publications
  The Sub-Unit Publications series contains publications from several programs for high school students, including the Program in Scholarly Research, The Wade McCree Incentive Scholars Program, and the King/Chavez/Parks Educational Initiative; the last of which has a College Day Program, as well as the KCP Visiting Professor program.
  - Faculty Awards Program
    - Guidelines, 1993 (Box 1)
  - King/Chavez/Parks Educational Initiative
    - KCP College Day Program
      - Brochures, 1989-1992; undated (Box 1)
    - KCP Educational Initiative State Report, 1990/91 (Box 1)
    - KCP Visiting Professor
      - Flyers, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
      - Proposals, 1991 (Box 1)
    - KCP Yearbook, 1988/89 (Box 1)
    - A Report on Martin Luther King, Jr.-Rosa Parks Educational Initiatives... fiscal year, 1986-1987 (Box 1)
  - The Program in Scholarly Research
    - Brochures, 1989-1990 (Box 1)
    - Participants' Working Brochure, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Student Academic Multicultural Initiatives
    - Brochures, 1993/94-1994/95 (Box 1)
  - The Wade McCree Incentive Scholars Program
    - Brochures, 1989 (Box 1)
    - Student Reports
      - The Art of Expression, 1991 (Box 1)
      - From Our Perspective, 1989 (Box 1)
      - Our Thought on the Subject...1995 (Box 1)